You'll never believe how close we came.
Thirteen Days is a history, thriller film directed by Roger Donaldson.
The story of the Cuban Missile Crisis in 1962—the nuclear standoff with the USSR sparked by the
discovery by the Americans of missile bases established on the Soviet-allied island of Cuba.
Kenneth O'Donnell, played by Kevin Costner.
John F. Kennedy, played by Bruce Greenwood.
Robert F. Kennedy, played by Steven Culp.
Robert McNamara, played by Dylan Baker.
Adlai Stevenson, played by Michael Fairman.
Dean Rusk, played by Henry Strozier.
Thirteen Days is a 2000 American historical political
thriller film directed by Roger Donaldson.
It dramatizes the Cuban Missile Crisis of 1962, seen from the
perspective of the American political leadership.
Kevin Costner stars as top White House assistant Kenneth P.
O'Donnell, with Bruce Greenwood featured as President John F.
Kennedy, Steven Culp as Attorney General Robert F.
Kennedy, and Dylan Baker as Secretary of Defense Robert McNamara.
While the film carries the same title as the 1969 book
Thirteen Days by former attorney general Robert F.
Kennedy, it is in fact based on the 1997 book, The Kennedy Tapes: Inside the
White House During the Cuban Missile Crisis, by Ernest R.
May and Philip D.
It is the second docudrama made about the crisis, the first being 1974's
The Missiles of October, which was based on Kennedy's book.
The 2000 film contains some newly declassified information not available to the earlier production, but
takes greater dramatic license, particularly in its choice of O'Donnell as protagonist.
It received generally positive reviews from critics who praised the screenplay and performances of the
cast but was a box-office bomb, grossing $66.6 million against its $80 million budget.
The film explores themes of usa president, politics,
atomic bomb, cold war, john f. kennedy.
The tone is intense.